BTS —11I(S)— 05.17 — 0720 Reg. No.
                                                                                     A


      Tech. Degree III Semester Supplementary Examination
                                     May 2017

                              CS 154302 LOGIC DESIGN
                                     (2015 Scheme)
   e: 3 Hours                                                      Maximum Marks:60
                                       PART A 
                                 (Answer ALL questions)
                                                                           (10 x 2 = 20)
I.   (a) Perform the following number conversions:
           (i) 567 in Octal to Hex
           (ii) 234.54 in decimal to binary.
     (b) Differentiate between canonical and standard forms of Boolean functions.
     (c) What are universal gates? Why are they called so?
     (d) What is carry look-ahead addition? What is the need?
     (e) Explain the design procedure of a combinational circuit.
     (f) Differentiate between synchronous and asynchronous circuits.
     (g) What is master slave flip flop?
     (h) Differentiate between PLA and PAL.
     (i) Write about ROM, PROM, EPROM and EEPROM.
     (j) Define the following terms: Fan out, Propagation delay and Noise margin.

                                       PART B
                                                                           (4 x 10 = 40)
II.        Simplify the following function using Quine McCluskey method.
           F(A,B,C,D)=1(0,2,3,5,7,8,9,10,11,13,15).
                                          OR
           Simplify the following expression using the K-Map method and implement 
           it using logic gates.
           (i) F = ACE + AlCD1E + A'C' DE.
           (ii) d = DE' + D E + AD 'E' .

IV.        Derive the expressions for a 4-bit magnitude comparator and implement it 
           using logic gates.
                                          OR
V.    (a) Design a decimal adder using 4-bit binary parallel adders.
      (b) Design an excess 3 to BCD code converter using a 4-bit binary parallel 
           adder.

VI.        Design a 4-bit Johnson counter. How does it differ from a ring counter? 
                                          OR
VII.       Design a 4-bit binary ripple counter using JK flip flops.

VIII.      Design a RAM consisting of four words of four bits each. Also show the 
           logic diagram of a typical binary cell.
                                          OR
1          Draw and explain the circuit for a TTL gate with Totem pole output driver.
                                          ***

